In this video we are going to continue our discussion of register interference graphs
在本视频中，我们将继续讨论寄存器干扰图
and talk about how to use RIGS to come up with register assignments for procedures.
并讨论如何使用钻机来设计程序的寄存器分配。
And we're going to look at one particular technique that's popular called graph
我们要看一下一种很流行的技术，叫做图形
coloring. So first, a couple of definitions. A graph coloring is an
上色。所以首先，有几个定义。图形着色是一种
assignment of colors to nodes such that the nodes connected by an edge have
为结点分配颜色，使边连接的结点具有
different colors. So if I have a graph let's say with, with three nodes and it's
不同的颜色。所以如果我有一个图，假设有三个节点，它是
fully connected so every node connect to every other node. And then, and then a
完全连接，因此每个节点都连接到所有其他节点。然后，然后是一个
coloring of this graph would be an assignment of colors such that every pair
此图的着色将是颜色的分配，以便每对颜色
of nodes are connected by an edge have a different color. So for example I could
的节点由具有不同颜色的边连接。举个例子，我可以
color this node blue and I could color this node green and I could color this
把这个节点涂成蓝色，我可以把这个节点涂成绿色，然后我可以给这个上色
node black, okay. And then that would be a valid coloring of the graph because each
节点黑，好的。然后这将是该图的有效着色，因为每个
pair of neighbours has a different color. And then the graph is k-colorable if it
一对邻居的颜色不同。则该图是k-可染的，如果
has a coloring that uses k or fewer colors. In our problem, the colors
具有使用k种或更少颜色的着色。在我们的问题中，颜色
corresponds to registers so we want to do is to assign colors or registers to the
对应于寄存器，因此我们要做的是将颜色或寄存器分配给
graph nodes. And we're going to let k, the number, the maximum number of colors we're
图形节点。我们要让k，我们的最大颜色数
allowed to use be the number of machine register. So the actual number of
允许使用的是机器注册号。所以实际的数字是
registers present on the architecture for which we're generating code. And then if,
我们正在为其生成代码的架构上存在的寄存器。然后如果
if a RIG, if a registered interference graph is k-colorable, then there's going
如果一个钻机，如果一个注册的干涉图是k-可染的，那么
to be a register assignment that uses no more than k registers. So let's take a
是使用不超过k个寄存器的寄存器赋值。所以让我们拿一个
look at an example rig and for this particular graph, there is no coloring. It
看一个示例装备，对于这个特定的图形，没有着色。它
turns out that it uses fewer than four colors. But there is at least one for
原来它使用的颜色不到四种。但至少有一个是
coloring of this graph. And then here it is so I've used colored labels but also
此图的着色。然后就是这里，所以我用了彩色标签，但是
register names so that you can see what registers we might assign to each of the
寄存器名称，以便您可以查看我们可能分配给每个
nodes. And just notice that although there are many more than four temporaries or
节点。请注意，尽管有四个以上的临时或
four nodes in this graph, we do manage to color it with only four colors and some of
这张图中有四个节点，我们只用四种颜色和一些
the nodes have the same color. So for example, d and b are allocated the same
节点具有相同的颜色。例如，d和b被分配相同的值
color, as are e and a. Just to remind ourselves where this register interference
颜色，就像e和a一样。只是为了提醒我们这个寄存器在哪里干扰
graph came from, here is the original control flow graph again. And, once we
图形来自，这里又是原始的控制流图。而且，一旦我们
have the coloring of the graph, now we can do the register assignment. We can replace
有了图的着色，现在我们可以做寄存器分配了。我们可以替换
the temporaries by their corresponding register names, and then we get this
通过它们对应的寄存器名称，我们就可以得到这样的结果
control flow graph. So, here we've just renamed each of the variables of the
控制流图。因此，在这里，我们刚刚重命名了
program with its register that it was assigned to. And now we're very close, as
程序及其分配给它的寄存器。现在我们非常接近了，因为
you can see, to having code that we can emit and execute on the target
您可以看到，拥有我们可以在目标上发出和执行的代码
architecture.
建筑。